<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one
  or more contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file
  distributed with this work for additional information
  regarding copyright ownership.  The ASF licenses this file
  to you under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the
  "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance
  with the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at

   http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
  software distributed under the License is distributed on an
  "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
  KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
  specific language governing permissions and limitations
  under the License.
-->
<content>
  <h2>About me</h2>
  
  <p>
    My name is Francesco Chicchiriccò, and my surname has been a tricky challenge since I was born in 1977, every time I had to get in touch with any public office; the advent of Internet made things even more cumbersome, despite of Unicode effort :-)
  </p>
  <p>
    My nickname at ASF is <b><i><a href="http://people.apache.org/list_C.html#ilgrosso">ilgrosso</a></i></b>, meaning &quot;the big one&quot; because, yeah, I don't wear a size S since I was 10 ;-)
    <br/>
    I am currently ASF member, <a href="http://syncope.apache.org">Apache Syncope</a> PMC chair, <a href="http://cocoon.apache.org">Apache Cocoon</a> PMC Member and <a href="http://olingo.incubator.apache.org/">Apache Olingo</a> PPMC member.
  </p>
  <p>
    Linux - then <a href="http://www.debian.org">Debian</a>, what else? - addict since 1997, I am Italian (and proud to be), married with my lovely wife Cinzia, father of two wonderful boys Davide and Mattia. Since I was a child I've always loved comics and music, playing bass guitar in a few metal rock bands with some friends.
  </p>
  <p>
    About Computer Science, I got a master degree in 2001 in <a href="http://www.di.univaq.it/">L'Aquila</a>, after six months spent at Nokia Research Center in Heksinki (about this, you can take a look at a <a href="linusphoto.html">photo</a> I took at that time with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linus_Torvalds">a friend of mine</a> :-P).
    <br/>
    Since then I've been working as developer, analyst and architect for some companies until I've established in 2004 my first IT company (ePOSSE, now <a href="http://www.everett.it">Everett Italia</a>). After seven years, I decided to start again from scratch with a brand new Open Source based company, <a href="http://www.tirasa.net">Tirasa</a>, aiming to speed up the development and the adoption of <a href="http://syncope.apache.org/">Apache Syncope</a>.
  </p>
  <p>
    In 2006 I had the chance to meet Gianugo Rabellino, at a common customer's place, that introduced to me the world of Apache Software Foundation in general and Cocoon in particular. Having suddenly realized that Cocoon 2.1 had an almost vertical learning curve, I've been anyway fascinated by the upsetting beauty of its architecture and potential.
    <br/>
    Besides ASF, I am project owner of <a href="http://tirasa.github.com/ConnId/">ConnId</a>, the <a href="http://tirasa.github.com/HippoCocoonToolkit/">Hippo Cocoon Toolkit</a> and <a href="https://github.com/Tirasa/OpenJPA-Azure">OpenJPA Azure</a>. I've been also contributing to some other projects like Sync4j (now <a href="http://www.funambol.com/opensource/">Funambol</a>), and <a href="http://www.hippocms.org">Hippo CMS</a>.
  </p>
</content>
